# Jay Gajjar

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

Location: Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

Email: gajjarjay.1711@gmail.com | Mobile: +919601287312

# Frontend Developer

I have total **6 years of experience** in **Frontend web development**, out of which **5 years** of relative experience in **Angular**.I also have basic knowledge of **NodeJs** library with Express and MongoDB which is used to create REST APIs.

# Experience

#### Sr. Frontend Developer

April 2019 - Present Ahmedabad, Gujarat

SoftrefineTechnologies

- Developed highly interactive web applications using TypeScript and Angular, with extensive integration of RESTful APIs.
- Built web pages that are more user-interactive using librarie like Ngx-bootstrap, Kendo UI, Angular Material, Mapbox.
- Experienced in creating server side scripts using nodejs.
- Interact with other developers and end users to design and implement new features throughout the framework.
- Worked extensively in using version control systems like GIT, Azure, Bitbucket and project management systems
  Jira, Trello.
- Used Jasmine/Karma for unit testing.
- Experience in CSS Flexbox layout, Consistency with browsers, Version and Platform Independence.

### **Frontend Developer**

November 2018 – March 2019 Ahmedabad, Gujarat

iCorethink Technologies

- Created Admin panel for organizational work.
- Implemented page designs in standard-complaint dynamic HTML and CSS.
- · Implemented client side validations in registration forms, login and logout forms using Angular.
- Responsible for code optimizing and testing across browsers.

### **Web Developer Intern**

Jan 2018 - Oct 2018

WebAgilent

Nadiad, Gujarat

Assisted senior web developers in the design and development of websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

### Education

# Government Engineering College Modasa (GTU),

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

Enrolled: June 2013 | Completed: June 2017 Overall CGPA: 7.10/10.00

### **Projects**

### Watering

Angular v16, KendoUI, MpboxJs, Angular PWA, Azure

- This provides solution for water networks in your area. It is using **mapboxJs and kendoUi library** to replicate installed water meters, sensors, pipes, pump and valves etc. on map view
- It measures how much pressure and flow running on specific pipe and indicate to sensors and user can check it through map view in monitor.
- It can run different types of analysis to find issues in water network into your area.

## QuizAcademy

Angular v19, Ngrx, websocket, Angular Material, bitbucket

- This is the simple and safe learning web app from Germany. With QuizAcademy, you as a teacher can create your
  own quizzes, exams and surveys, make them available to your learners and analyze the results.
- It's a multilingual site uses Angular Material and NGRX to manage different environment for teacher, students etc. It consists of end-to-end test cases created using Protractor, Jasmine and Karma that perform tests on the whole application as a way how users interact with it.

### **Blu Loyalty**

Angular v12, Angular Material, ng-select, Git Submodules

- blu loyalty offers end-to-end customer loyalty and customer engagement ready programs to virtually any type of business.
- Worked on several blu loyalty's partners websites which uses Angular material components, that run and manage a loyalty program such as the complete management of a reward catalog for merchandise items and travel services.

### Deportevalenciano

Angular v9, Angular Universal, GIT, Hasura GraphQL

- A valencian sports news website that provides information about latest Valencian sports news, rumors of the Valencian soccer teams and signings of Valencia, Villarreal, Levante and the Valencian teams
- To reduce website load time and improve google pageinsight score, It was created with Angular Serverside Rendering(SSR) implementation with help of Angular Universal.

## **Technical Skills**

**Languages** : JavaScript, Typescript **Frameworks/Library** : Angular, Express, Node.js

Libraries : Angular Material, NGRX, Mapbox, AgGrid, KendoUI, Ngx-bootstrap

**Version Control** : GIT, Microsoft Azure, Gitlab, Jira, Trello and Bitbucket

**Databases** : MongoDB, MYSQL

**Dev Tools** : Visual Studio Code, Git, Gitlab